every Trader that watches this video
will have a complete understanding of
Forex let's get it so first off what is
Forex Forex is the largest and most
liquid Market in the world and it trades
on average about $6.6 trillion dollar
per day now what that means for us as
Traders is that we're never going to
have a problem getting our order filled
Forex is a global Marketplace for
exchanging National currencies and the
way we use this as Traders is that in
Forex we're trading based on something
called a currency pair which we'll talk
about in a second and this currency pair
is nothing more than the exchange rate
between two different countries and this
exchange rate fluctuates Up and Down
based on the different strengths and
weaknesses of an economy for a specific
currency along with many other factors
and as Traders we use information that
we gather from technical analysis and
fundamental analysis along with news
events in order to predict these
fluctuations in prices and trade
accordingly now as I just said Forex is
traded in something called a currency
pair the very next thing we're going to
do is take a look at what is a currency
pair a currency pair is exactly what it
sounds like it is two separate
currencies in a pair and we use this
currency pair to determine the exchange
rate of two separate currencies to make
this more clear you can see on the
screen we have the Aussie dollar and
what I'll do is I'll also put a
screenshot of every three-letter
abbreviation that equals a specific
currency on the screen somewhere right
now and these threel symbols again
represent a specific currency so in this
case we have the AUD which would be the
Australian dollar versus the USD which
would be the United States dollar in a
currency pair the first currency in this
pair is what is known as the base
currency and the base currency is always
equal to one the second currency in a
currency pair is what is known as the
quote currency the quote currency is the
quote you actually see on the screen so
the way to look at this is it takes one
Australian dollar and if I have one
Australian dollar I have roughly Z
654 cents of United States dollar
currency so that means it takes roughly
65 cents USD to equal $1 Australian
dollar so in this case I want to ask you
which currency is stronger at this
moment well if we only need 65 cents USD
in order to equal one Australian dollar
then the USD is stronger than the
Australian dollar at this moment let's
do this one more time with another
example on the screen you can see that
we have the euro versus the dollar so if
we have Euro versus dollar which one of
these is going to be the base currency
that's going to be the Euros that means
the euro is going to be equal to one
then we have the dollar which is what
it's called the quote currency since the
dollar is the quote currency that means
it takes $ 1.07
one3 USD to equal one Euro so let's go
ahead and put that down we have
1.07 one3 I know my handwriting is
awesome and so now we know that the euro
is stronger than the dollar at the
moment because it takes us 1.07 or $17
to equal € at this moment and for a last
example I want you to do this one
completely which one of these in the cad
yen is going to be the base currency now
which one's the quote currency and which
one is represented by this number so
hopefully you said that the Canada was
the base currency hopefully you said the
yin was the quote currency and hopefully
you said the 102. 63 was how many Yen it
would take to equal one Canadian dollar
now let's move on to brokers so what is
a Forex broker a Forex broker is just a
financial services company that acts as
a middleman between us as Traders and
the Forex Market itself it's how we
actually Place trades now in terms of
Forex Brokers there's plenty of options
out there the only things that I'm going
to say here is that you want to make
sure you find a regulated broker that's
regulated in a country you've heard of
so not a broker that's registered and
regulated in the Cayman Islands that's
something you would not want because
there you're running the risk of that
broker shutting down going bankrupt and
you losing all of your money so you
don't want to find a broker that's
either not regulated or not regulated in
a country that you have heard of but as
long as you have a broker that's
registered and regulated in a country
you've heard from you're probably in the
clear the other thing you want to look
out for is you want to find a broker
that has competitive spreads spreads are
how Brokers make money some Brokers are
going to have higher spreads than others
so you want to make sure to find a
broker that has competitive spreads and
outside of that this broker is going to
need to cater to your own personal needs
so it may be different for everyone for
me my personal broker is aanda they're
not sponsoring this video I don't have
any kind of affiliate link with them
whatsoever I've just used them forever
and it's who I use right now feel free
to check them out at oanda.com now your
broker may have a trading platform that
comes with it but they're normally not
that good so the next thing you're going
to need after a broker is an actual
trading platform you've probably heard
of mt4 and mt5 my favorite though is
tradingview.com so this is my trading
platform that I use on a daily basis
it's an online trading platform meaning
you don't have to download anything to
access it and it's got everything anyone
would ever need it's got every indicator
you can think of it's got all different
types of tools that can help you make
trading as smooth as possible which is
very necessary in my opinion if you want
a full tutorial on this platform I'll
put it in the top right corner of the
screen along with in the description
I've made like a 20 minute tutorial that
goes through every part of trading View
and teaches you exactly how to use this
trading platform if you're interested in
that check out that video but one of my
favorite parts of trading view is that I
can connect my broker to this trading
platform and I don't have to switch back
and forth between my broker and my
trading platform in order to place
actual trades so right now what I want
to do is show you how to connect your
broker to trading view if this is
something you decide to do also feel
free to check out trading view by going
to
www.tradingview.com so in order to
connect your broker to trade trading
view all you need to do is come down
here to trading panel you can make this
as large as you want to I hit see all
Brokers and at this point just look
through the list of Brokers that are
available in your area and make the
decision on whether or not you would
like to connect your broker with trading
view now if your broker is not on this
list that simply means that they cannot
connect with trading view at this time
and you'll have to find a different
trading platform or do as I used to do
and go back and forth between your
trading platform and your actual
brokerage account in order to place
trades so now that you know a little bit
about Brokers trading platforms and how
to connect a trading platform to trading
view let's move on now and talk about
what is a pip so a pip is how the Forex
Market moves it stands for percentage in
points and what's really important for
you to understand is what a pip is a pip
is the fourth place after the decimal so
right here we're looking at the euro
dollar this is the important part what
you really need to understand is that a
single pip is the fourth place after the
decimal if we go 1 2 3 4 which one of
these numbers is a pip the fourth one so
the nine here is one pip what that means
is that if we go from 1.0079 on the euro
dollar to
1.07
08 we have now went down the price of
the Euro against the dollar has went
down one pip so that's how you calculate
and find a pip and how much prices move
is based on these Pips so let's go ahead
and do another example here what if we
go to one
.08
09 at this point how many Pips has price
went up well we've went up 100 Pips so
the nine is the ones the zero here would
be the tens the seven would be the
hundreds that's how we calculate
everything let's do two more examples
really quickly it's just easy math so
you should be able to get a hang of this
pretty quickly what if we go to
1.07 1 0 how much did we go up we went
up one pip because we went from 09 to 10
one more example here what if we go to
1.07
01 how many Pips did price move lower we
moved lower by eight Pips because we
went from 09 to 01 meaning we went down
8 Pips in this example now this four
decimal point to the PIP is true for
every currency pair except Yen crosses
except pairs that have JPY in them so
what we're going to do now that you
understand a regular currency pair in
terms of Pips where the PIP is and how
to determine how much of currency pairs
went up and down using Pips let's now
take a look at a JPY pair and where the
PIP is on those pairs so as I said on a
regular currency pair everything but Yen
pairs the PIP is going to be the fourth
place after the decimal which means we
can't have that on a Yen pair because on
Yen pairs we only have two places after
the decimal so for Yen pairs the PIP is
the second place after the decimal so
one two that would mean the six right
here is the PIP counter for the dollar
Yen so if the dollar Yen goes from
139.99 to 139
97 how much did the dollar Yen go up it
went up by one pip let's do a couple
more examples what if we go to
13986 how much do we go down we went
down by 10 Pips so now that you know
what a pip is and how we can determine
how much prices of a currency pair have
went up and down by using Pips what is a
pip worth how to calculate the value of
a pip is what we're going to take a look
at right now while in a trade in the
Forex Market as the market moves up and
down we're obviously making and losing
money depending on what position we have
on now with the market moving in Pips we
need to know another side to this
equation to understand what the value of
each pip as price moves is going to be
worth how much is it going to take out
and add to our account as prices go up
and down the way we determine that is
through the position size that we are
using so each pip can be worth a
completely different amount depending on
your position size luckily there are
position size calculators that do all
this work for us but I'm going to show
you a chart that gives you a general
rule for position sizing and how much
each pip will be worth based on the
position size that you have let's take a
look at that right now so here that is
and what we can see here is a nano lot
is about 100 units of currency and 100
units of currency means that generally
you'll be making and losing about 1 cent
per pip as we go up you can see that
these numbers go up so as we go to a
micro lot which is 1,000 units of
currency being your position size you're
going to be making and losing about 10
cents per pip as we go up to a mini lot
which is 10,000 units of currency you're
going to be making and losing about $1
per pip and as we go up to a standard
lot we're going to be making and losing
$10 for every single pip price moves up
or down so again that is a
generalization and a general rule of how
much each pip is going to be worth it's
a little bit different for every
currency pair but this is a good
generalization and again fortunately for
us we do not need to know this at all
because there's something called
position size calculators which I'm
going to show you right now just in case
that wasn't completely clear as price
moves up and down after we've placed an
order it's doing so obviously in Pips
and as price goes up a certain certain
amount of Pips we're going to make a
certain amount of money if we Bol at a
certain price as price goes down we're
going to lose a certain amount of money
and each pip can be worth different
amounts depending yet again on our
position size so hopefully that clears
any doubts up about that situation our
position size is going to be what
determines the value of a pip as price
moves up and down while we're inside of
a trade now let's take a look at a
position siiz calculator I like to
personally use this position siiz
calculator is on myfxbook.com you can
literally just type in position siiz
calculator for Forex on Google it'll be
one of the first like five that pop up
or you can just go to the link you can
see right under the video and this makes
determining the value of a pip extremely
easy without you having to do any math
at all all you have to do is put in the
currency pair you're trading put in your
account currency then you're going to
put in your account size let's say you
have $110,000 account the next thing you
can do is type in what percent of your
account you want to risk let's go with a
2% risk and then we're going to need
your stop loss let's say that the amount
you're willing to lose on that trade is
about 20 Pips now all you have to do is
hit calculate and this will show you the
exact amount of units that you need in
order to place this specific trade so a
position size calculator is going to be
the way to go instead of trying to
determine the value of a pip by using a
bunch of math instead of that let's just
use the position size calculator because
if it's here why would we not use it to
save some time now as I said in order to
use this correctly you're going to need
to know what your stop- loss is in Pips
and for that reason what I want to do
right now is go through what a stop-
loss is how you can set a stoploss
correctly and talk a little bit about
risk management along with leverage so a
stop- loss is going to be a main
contributor to our risk management plan
a stop- loss is going to be a price that
we go okay I was wrong about this trade
and I want to go ahead and get out cut
my losses and move on to the next one so
let's say here on the pound dollar that
I'm expecting a bounce out of price
because of the fact that we're at a
previous level of structure that's been
tested multiple times and I see this
little dogee happening so I'm like cool
I want to buy this right now well a good
place for a stop in my opinion and for
my own personal trading would be below
this Zone because if price in fact
breaks below this Zone then my analysis
is no longer true this area is not
holding up price if price goes below it
hopefully that makes sense so this might
be an area that I put my stop- loss and
the exact price of this would be
1.246 now for a risk management plan
something we have to determine is how
much of my account am I willing to lose
on this specific trade so if I have
roughly 43 Pips down to my stop loss how
much does each pip need to be worth for
me to risk 1 to 2% of my account on this
trade let me make that more clear so
let's say I have a 10K account and I
want to risk 2% meaning I want to risk
$200 okay well in that case how much
does each pip need to be worth in order
for 43 Pips to equal my $200 loss now we
could do some simple math and figure
that up or we can take the easy route
and just go back over to our position
size calculator we're on the pound
dollar that's what we're going to do by
the way so we're on the pound dollar
let's go over here to the position size
calculator we'll type in pound dollar
we'll go ahead and click that we our
account currency is
$10,000 and our risk we're trying to
take on this trade is 2% just so you
know an average across retail Traders is
somewhere between 1% and 2% of their
total account value is what a lot of
retail professional Traders are going to
be risking so we're going to go with 2%
in this case and our stop loss in Pips
was
42.8 Pips we're going to call it 43 Pips
so we'll do 43 and then we'll click
calculate and what you'll notice is this
does all the work for you it gives you
the exact position size that you need
which is
46,51 12 units or 047 Lots in order for
this to be true on your trade in order
for your stop loss on your trade to
equal $200 that's the position size
you're going to need to use is
46,51 12 units for this pound doll trade
so that's a little bit about risk
management how we can utilize stop
losses along with our position size
calculator in order to make risk
management extremely easy in terms of
actually placing the stop-loss in your
brokerage account it's going to depend a
little bit on your brokerage or your
trading platform in trading view I just
rightclick the chart click create new
order if I wanted to buy the pound
dollar at market right now all I would
need to do is hit stoploss you can see
the number for my stop- loss is in the
exact price
right here it's
1.246 so I would go for the price of the
stop loss
1.246 you'd also go up here to your
percent risk and do whatever you would
like let's say it's 2% here in this case
so that would be the actual process of
placing the stop-loss order as you're
buying or after you buy a specific trade
here on trading view as I said it'll be
slightly different depending on the
platform and broker that you use now
let's move on so I can teach you about
leverage Leverage is probably one of the
most most complicated subjects for 90%
of people that attempt to start Forex
Trading but I'm going to make this very
simple I promise leverages the use of
borrowed funds from your broker in order
for you to be able to have larger
positions it gives you a ability to have
a larger position size and what did we
just say about Pips every pip the market
moves while you're in a trade is going
to be worth a certain amount that number
the amount each pip is worth goes up
depending on your position size the
bigger the position size the more each
pip is worth so with that being the case
obviously leverage can help you grow an
account faster because each pip can be
worth more but it can also cause you to
have much larger losses than you
initially could with your own account
balance so that is why it's so important
to understand risk management stop
losses and only risk a very small
portion of your account per trade before
even talking about leverage that's the
whole reason we just did that entire
section first so let's dive deep into
leverage right now let's say that you
have a $10,000 account and you have no
leverage at all in this case what is
your maximum position size your maximum
position size that you can have in a
trade or in the Market at all is just
your 10,000 units so this would be your
maximum position size with zero leverage
and what I want you to do is to start
thinking of Leverage not as some
complicated thing you have to try to
figure out but as your maximum position
size your leveraged account let's go
with a 10:1 leverage to keep math very
simple but it's going to be the same for
any leverage you use the numbers are
just going to change based on what
leverage amount you have we're going to
go with a 10:1 leverage so on a $10,000
account with 10 to1 leverage now instead
of your maximum position size you can
have it any one time in the market being
10,000 it's now
100,000 units now the wrong way to use
leverage would be to go out and just
place a trade with 100,000 units because
that means that each pip is going to be
worth 10 bucks you only have 100 Pips
before you blow your entire account that
would not be the right way to use
leverage but what leverage can help us
do is what if we wanted to be in three
different trades all at a 2% or less
risk well we couldn't do that more than
likely with just 10,000 units of Maximum
position size we can do that now by
utilizing leverage which in my opinion
in the way I trade this is going to be
the correct way to use Leverage is to
use it in order to be in more trades at
once not necessarily in order to just
place a trade with the largest position
size possible so again replace the word
leverage with your maximum position size
Leverage is not your broker telling you
hey you can borrow a
$100,000 and you can lose $100,000 we'll
only take 10 grand from you you can lose
a full 100 that's fine that's on us that
is a very common misconception that's
not true at all your Leverage is just
the maximum position size you can hold
at once when your account drops and you
lose $10,000 you're going to get a
margin call they're going to take the
position off themselves and you're going
to have your account being completely
blown you can't lose $100,000 because
you have 10:1 leverage on a 10K account
that's not how it works again Leverage
is your maximum position size your
maximum buying power this is the amount
of units you can hold in your account at
any one given time so with that being
the case to make this a little more
clear let's go through a couple of
hypothetical trades and you tell me
whether or not you could place that
trade with a $10,000 account using 10
to1 leverage well use the same pound
dollar trade as our first example so on
this trade remember the 43 Pips is our
stop loss but let's say you wanted to
risk $500 this time you said hey I'm
going to risk a little more than normal
I'm going to go with a $500 risk that's
5% of the account and what we have to do
now is figure out what position size do
we need for this stop loss to equal $500
remember we have a 10K account with 10
to one leverage meaning we have 100k
buying power we can open a maximum
position of 100,000 units let's go over
to the position size calculator hit the
pound dollar yet again and we're looking
at an account size of
$10,000 we're looking at a risk of $500
by the way you can swap this from
percent to regular money just like that
we're going to be looking at a $500 risk
and remember our stop loss was 43 Pips
so if I hit calculate I'm going to ask
you a very serious question after
learning what you have about leverage
we're risking $500 on a $10,000 account
be honest do you think you should be
able to place that
trade so many of you probably just said
yes you're thinking oh it's just $500
risk on a $110,000 account why wouldn't
I be able to place that trade
remember Leverage is our maximum buying
power and with the leverage we have
currently that we've discussed
throughout this video 10K account 10:1
leverage what's our Max buying power
100K units now I want you to look at the
units and look how much we would need to
place this trade in order to place this
trade we would need
116,000 units our Max buying power with
Leverage is only 100,000 units so even
though all we're trying to do is risk
$500 on a $10,000 account which I know
seems like it should be capable you
should be able to do that you can't do
that because your broker is only giving
you 10 to one leverage you have a Max
buying power of 100K units and that's
the reason you can't place this specific
trade so hopefully that clears up a
little bit about leverage let's take a
look at one more example let's just
change this trade up and say we wanted
to risk
$300 calculate now we don't have to go
through much you should know by now that
you have a 10K account you have 10 to
one L leverage you have 100,000 units of
buying power in this case could you
place this
trade yes because all you need is 69,000
units in order to place this trade so
remember Leverage is not the amount you
can use and just because all you want to
risk is $500 on a $10,000 account
doesn't mean you're going to be able to
because what you have to think about and
look at is your max buying power
otherwise known as leverage so if you
only have 100k of Max buying power then
the largest position you can open is
going to be 100,000 unit position and
again this works across everything if
you had a 10K account and let's say you
had 50 to one leverage your max buying
power now is
500,000 units again it's just simple
math combining your leverage with your
account or multiplying it in order to
figure out your leverage and or Max
buying power learning what you just did
about the basics of Forex is a great
start but in order to be a successful
Trader and ever start making real money
from Trading there's three important
skills you must master in the middle of
this triangle is everyone making money
from their trading all of them have
mastered a strategy or strategies that
make money over time they've all
mastered their risk management and
they've all mastered their mindset we
call this trading psychology and right
now I'm looking for 500 new or
struggling traders to mentor and teach
each of these very important skills to
and help guide all 500 of these traders
to trading success so throughout this
process you'll not only get access to
all the strategies techniques tips and
tricks that I've learned about trading
throughout my decade of trading
experience but it's also a full Mentor
program where you'll have access to me
to answer any of the questions that you
may have you'll also be getting some of
my own personal trading setups each and
every week and on top of that we are
giving the first 500 people to join us a
massive $500 discount on the yearly
subscription this offer also comes with
a 30-day money back guarantee so if
you'd like to take me up on that sort of
risk-free offer and if that sounds like
something that's interesting to you go
ahead and go to www. thetradingcarder
that's completely fine too just be sure
you're subscribed here to get a first
look at all the trading related content
we come out with each and every week go
ahe hit that like button if you made it
to the end let me know in the comments
section I wish you the best of luck on
all your future trades and I'll catch
you in the next video see you soon